IV

Good Hunting

When we had got that four shillings by digging for treasure we ought, by rights, to have tried Dicky’s idea of answering the advertisement about ladies and gentlemen and spare time and two pounds a week, but there were several things we rather wanted.

Dora wanted a new pair of scissors, and she said she was going to get them with her eightpence. But Alice said—

“You ought to get her those, Oswald, because you know you broke the points off hers getting the marble out of the brass thimble.”

It was quite true, though I had almost forgotten it, but then it was H. O. who jammed the marble into the thimble first of all. So I said—

“It’s H. O.’s fault as much as mine, anyhow. Why shouldn’t he pay?”

Oswald didn’t so much mind paying for the beastly scissors, but he hates injustice of every kind.

“He’s such a little kid,” said Dicky, and of course H. O. said he wasn’t a little kid, and it very nearly came to being a row between them. But Oswald knows when to be generous; so he said—

“Look here! I’ll pay sixpence of the scissors, and H. O. shall pay the rest, to teach him to be careful.”

H. O. agreed: he is not at all a mean kid, but I found out afterwards that Alice paid his share out of her own money.

Then we wanted some new paints, and Noël wanted a pencil and a halfpenny account-book to write poetry with, and it does seem hard never to have any apples. So, somehow or other nearly all the money got spent, and we agreed that we must let the advertisement run loose a little longer.

“I only hope,” Alice said, “that they won’t have got all the ladies and gentlemen they want before we have got the money to write for the sample and instructions.”

And I was a little afraid myself, because it seemed such a splendid chance; but we looked in the paper every day, and the advertisement was always there, so we thought it was all right.

Then we had the detective try-on—and it proved no go; and then, when all the money was gone, except a halfpenny of mine and twopence of Noël’s and threepence of Dicky’s and a few pennies that the girls had left, we held another council.

Dora was sewing the buttons on H. O.’s Sunday things. He got himself a knife with his money, and he cut every single one of his best buttons off. You’ve no idea how many buttons there are on a suit. Dora counted them. There are twenty-four, counting the little ones on the sleeves that don’t undo.

Alice was trying to teach Pincher to beg; but he has too much sense when he knows you’ve got nothing in your hands, and the rest of us were roasting potatoes under the fire. We had made a fire on purpose, though it was rather warm. They are very good if you cut away the burnt parts—but you ought to wash them first, or you are a dirty boy.

“Well, what can we do?” said Dicky. “You are so fond of saying ‘Let’s do something!’ and never saying what.”

“We can’t try the advertisement yet. Shall we try rescuing someone?” said Oswald. It was his own idea, but he didn’t insist on doing it, though he is next to the eldest, for he knows it is bad manners to make people do what you want, when they would rather not.

“What was Noël’s plan?” Alice asked.

“A Princess or a poetry book,” said Noël sleepily. He was lying on his back on the sofa, kicking his legs. “Only I shall look for the Princess all by myself. But I’ll let you see her when we’re married.”

“Have you got enough poetry to make a book?” Dicky asked that, and it was rather sensible of him, because when Noël came to look there were only seven of his poems that any of us could understand. There was the “Wreck of the Malabar,” and the poem he wrote when Eliza took us to hear the Reviving Preacher, and everybody cried, and Father said it must have been the Preacher’s Eloquence.

So Noël wrote—

O Eloquence and what art thou?
Ay what art thou? because we cried
And everybody cried inside
When they came out their eyes were red—
And it was your doing Father said.

But Noël told Alice he got the first line and a half from a book a boy at school was going to write when he had time. Besides this there were the “Lines on a Dead Black Beetle that was poisoned”—

O Beetle how I weep to see
Thee lying on thy poor back!
It is so very sad indeed.
You were so shiny and black.
I wish you were alive again
But Eliza says wishing it is nonsense and a shame

It was very good beetle poison, and there were hundreds of them lying dead—but Noël only wrote a piece of poetry for one of them. He said he hadn’t time to do them all, and the worst of it was he didn’t know which one he’d written it to—so Alice couldn’t bury the beetle and put the lines on its grave, though she wanted to very much.

Well, it was quite plain that there wasn’t enough poetry for a book.

“We might wait a year or two,” said Noël. “I shall be sure to make some more some time. I thought of a piece about a fly this morning that knew condensed milk was sticky.”

“But we want the money now,” said Dicky, “and you can go on writing just the same. It will come in some time or other.”

“There’s poetry in newspapers,” said Alice. “Down, Pincher! you’ll never be a clever dog, so it’s no good trying.”

“Do they pay for it?” Dicky thought of that; he often thinks of things that are really important, even if they are a little dull.

“I don’t know. But I shouldn’t think anyone would let them print their poetry without. I wouldn’t I know.” That was Dora; but Noël said he wouldn’t mind if he didn’t get paid, so long as he saw his poetry printed and his name at the end.

“We might try, anyway,” said Oswald. He is always willing to give other people’s ideas a fair trial.

So we copied out “The Wreck of the Malabar” and the other six poems on drawing-paper—Dora did it, she writes best—and Oswald drew a picture of the Malabar going down with all hands. It was a full-rigged schooner, and all the ropes and sails were correct; because my cousin is in the Navy, and he showed me.

We thought a long time whether we’d write a letter and send it by post with the poetry—and Dora thought it would be best. But Noël said he couldn’t bear not to know at once if the paper would print the poetry, So we decided to take it.

I went with Noël, because I am the eldest, and he is not old enough to go to London by himself. Dicky said poetry was rot—and he was glad he hadn’t got to make a fool of himself. That was because there was not enough money for him to go with us. H. O. couldn’t come either, but he came to the station to see us off, and waved his cap and called out “Good hunting!” as the train started.

There was a lady in spectacles in the corner. She was writing with a pencil on the edges of long strips of paper that had print all down them. When the train started she asked—

“What was that he said?”

So Oswald answered—

“It was ‘Good hunting’—it’s out of the Jungle Book!” “That’s very pleasant to hear,” the lady said; “I am very pleased to meet people who know their Jungle Book. And where are you off to—the Zoological Gardens to look for Bagheera?”

We were pleased, too, to meet someone who knew the Jungle Book.

So Oswald said—

“We are going to restore the fallen fortunes of the House of Bastable—and we have all thought of different ways—and we’re going to try them all. Noël’s way is poetry. I suppose great poets get paid?”

The lady laughed—she was awfully jolly—and said she was a sort of poet, too, and the long strips of paper were the proofs of her new book of stories. Because before a book is made into a real book with pages and a cover, they sometimes print it all on strips of paper, and the writer make marks on it with a pencil to show the printers what idiots they are not to understand what a writer means to have printed.

We told her all about digging for treasure, and what we meant to do. Then she asked to see Noël’s poetry—and he said he didn’t like—so she said, “Look here—if you’ll show me yours I’ll show you some of mine.” So he agreed.

The jolly lady read Noël’s poetry, and she said she liked it very much. And she thought a great deal of the picture of the Malabar. And then she said, “I write serious poetry like yours myself; too, but I have a piece here that I think you will like because it’s about a boy.” She gave it to us—and so I can copy it down, and I will, for it shows that some grownup ladies are not so silly as others. I like it better than Noël’s poetry, though I told him I did not, because he looked as if he was going to cry. This was very wrong, for you should always speak the truth, however unhappy it makes people. And I generally do. But I did not want him crying in the railway carriage.

The lady’s piece of poetry:—

Oh when I wake up in my bed
And see the sun all fat and red,
I’m glad to have another day
For all my different kinds of play.

There are so many things to do—
The things that make a man of you,
If grownups did not get so vexed
And wonder what you will do next.

I often wonder whether they
Ever made up our kinds of play—
If they were always good as gold
And only did what they were told

They like you best to play with tops
And toys in boxes, bought in shops;
They do not even know the names
Of really interesting games.

They will not let you play with fire
Or trip your sister up with wire,
They grudge the tea-tray for a drum,
Or booby-traps when callers come.

They don’t like fishing, and it’s true
You sometimes soak a suit or two:
They look on fireworks, though they’re dry,
With quite a disapproving eye.

They do not understand the way
To get the most out of your day:
They do not know how hunger feels
Nor what you need between your meals.

And when you’re sent to bed at night,
They’re happy, but they’re not polite.
For through the door you hear them say:
“He’s done his mischief for the day!”

She told us a lot of other pieces but I cannot remember them, and she talked to us all the way up, and when we got nearly to Cannon Street she said—

“I’ve got two new shillings here! Do you think they would help to smooth the path to Fame?”

Noël said, “Thank you,” and was going to take the shilling. But Oswald, who always remembers what he is told, said—

“Thank you very much, but Father told us we ought never to take anything from strangers.”

“That’s a nasty one,” said the lady—she didn’t talk a bit like a real lady, but more like a jolly sort of grownup boy in a dress and hat—“a very nasty one! But don’t you think as Noël and I are both poets I might be considered a sort of relation? You’ve heard of brother poets, haven’t you? Don’t you think Noël and I are aunt and nephew poets, or some relationship of that kind?”

I didn’t know what to say, and she went on—

“It’s awfully straight of you to stick to what your Father tells you, but look here, you take the shillings, and here’s my card. When you get home tell your Father all about it, and if he says No, you can just bring the shillings back to me.”

So we took the shillings, and she shook hands with us and said, “Goodbye, and good hunting!”

We did tell Father about it, and he said it was all right, and when he looked at the card he told us we were highly honoured, for the lady wrote better poetry than any other lady alive now. We had never heard of her, and she seemed much too jolly for a poet. Good old Kipling! We owe him those two shillings, as well as the Jungle Books!

VIII

Being Editors

It was Albert’s uncle who thought of our trying a newspaper. He said he thought we should not find the bandit business a paying industry, as a permanency, and that journalism might be.

We had sold Noël’s poetry and that piece of information about Lord Tottenham to the good editor, so we thought it would not be a bad idea to have a newspaper of our own. We saw plainly that editors must be very rich and powerful, because of the grand office and the man in the glass case, like a museum, and the soft carpets and big writing-table. Besides our having seen a whole handful of money that the editor pulled out quite carelessly from his trousers pocket when he gave me my five bob.

Dora wanted to be editor and so did Oswald, but he gave way to her because she is a girl, and afterwards he knew that it is true what it says in the copy-books about Virtue being its own Reward. Because you’ve no idea what a bother it is. Everybody wanted to put in everything just as they liked, no matter how much room there was on the page. It was simply awful! Dora put up with it as long as she could and then she said if she wasn’t let alone she wouldn’t go on being editor; they could be the paper’s editors themselves, so there.

Then Oswald said, like a good brother: “I will help you if you like, Dora,” and she said, “You’re more trouble than all the rest of them! Come and be editor and see how you like it. I give it up to you.” But she didn’t, and we did it together. We let Albert-next-door be sub-editor, because he had hurt his foot with a nail in his boot that gathered.

When it was done Albert-next-door’s uncle had it copied for us in typewriting, and we sent copies to all our friends, and then of course there was no one left that we could ask to buy it. We did not think of that until too late. We called the paper the Lewisham Recorder; Lewisham because we live there, and Recorder in memory of the good editor. I could write a better paper on my head, but an editor is not allowed to write all the paper. It is very hard, but he is not. You just have to fill up with what you can get from other writers. If I ever have time I will write a paper all by myself. It won’t be patchy. We had no time to make it an illustrated paper, but I drew the ship going down with all hands for the first copy. But the typewriter can’t draw ships, so it was left out in the other copies. The time the first paper took to write out no one would believe! This was the Newspaper:

The Lewisham Recorder

Editors: Dora and Oswald Bastable

Editorial Note.

Every paper is written for some reason. Ours is because we want to sell it and get money. If what we have written brings happiness to any sad heart we shall not have laboured in vain. But we want the money too. Many papers are content with the sad heart and the happiness, but we are not like that, and it is best not to be deceitful.—Editors.

There will be two serial stories; One by Dicky and one by all of us. In a serial story you only put in one chapter at a time. But we shall put all our serial story at once, if Dora has time to copy it. Dicky’s will come later on.

Serial Story

by us all

Chapter I

—by Dora

The sun was setting behind a romantic-looking tower when two strangers might have been observed descending the crest of the hill. The eldest, a man in the prime of life; the other a handsome youth who reminded everybody of Quentin Durward. They approached the Castle, in which the fair Lady Alicia awaited her deliverers. She leaned from the castellated window and waved her lily hand as they approached. They returned her signal, and retired to seek rest and refreshment at a neighbouring hostelry.

Chapter II

—by Alice

The Princess was very uncomfortable in the tower, because her fairy godmother had told her all sorts of horrid things would happen if she didn’t catch a mouse every day, and she had caught so many mice that now there were hardly any left to catch. So she sent her carrier pigeon to ask the noble Strangers if they could send her a few mice—because she would be of age in a few days and then it wouldn’t matter. So the fairy godmother—(I’m very sorry, but there’s no room to make the chapters any longer.-Ed.)

Chapter III

—by the Sub-Editor

(I can’t—I’d much rather not—I don’t know how.)

Chapter IV

—by Dicky

I must now retrace my steps and tell you something about our hero. You must know he had been to an awfully jolly school, where they had turkey and goose every day for dinner, and never any mutton, and as many helps of pudding as a fellow cared to send up his plate for—so of course they had all grown up very strong, and before he left school he challenged the Head to have it out man to man, and he gave it him, I tell you. That was the education that made him able to fight Red Indians, and to be the stranger who might have been observed in the first chapter.

Chapter V

—by Noël

I think it’s time something happened in this story. So then the dragon he came out, blowing fire out of his nose, and he said—

“Come on, you valiant man and true,
I’d like to have a set-to along of you!”

(That’s bad English.—Ed. I don’t care; it’s what the dragon said. Who told you dragons didn’t talk bad English?—Noël.)

So the hero, whose name was Noeloninuris, replied—

“My blade is sharp, my axe is keen,
You’re not nearly as big As a good many dragons I’ve seen.”

(Don’t put in so much poetry, Noël. It’s not fair, because none of the others can do it.—Ed.)

And then they went at it, and he beat the dragon, just as he did the Head in Dicky’s part of the Story, and so he married the Princess, and they lived—(No they didn’t—not till the last chapter.—Ed.)

Chapter VI

—by H. O.

I think it’s a very nice Story—but what about the mice? I don’t want to say any more. Dora can have what’s left of my chapter.

Chapter VII

—by the Editors

And so when the dragon was dead there were lots of mice, because he used to kill them for his tea but now they rapidly multiplied and ravaged the country, so the fair lady Alicia, sometimes called the Princess, had to say she would not marry any one unless they could rid the country of this plague of mice. Then the Prince, whose real name didn’t begin with N, but was Osrawalddo, waved his magic sword, and the dragon stood before them, bowing gracefully. They made him promise to be good, and then they forgave him; and when the wedding breakfast came, all the bones were saved for him. And so they were married and lived happy ever after.

(What became of the other stranger?—Noël. The dragon ate him because he asked too many questions.—Editors.)

This is the end of the story.

Instructive

It only takes four hours and a quarter now to get from London to Manchester; but I should not think any one would if they could help it.

A Dreadful Warning. A wicked boy told me a very instructive thing about ginger. They had opened one of the large jars, and he happened to take out quite a lot, and he made it all right by dropping marbles in, till there was as much ginger as before. But he told me that on the Sunday, when it was coming near the part where there is only juice generally, I had no idea what his feelings were. I don’t see what he could have said when they asked him. I should be sorry to act like it.

Scientific

Experiments should always be made out of doors. And don’t use benzoline.—Dicky.

(That was when he burnt his eyebrows off.—Ed.)

The earth is 2,400 miles round, and 800 through—at least I think so, but perhaps it’s the other way.—Dicky.

(You ought to have been sure before you began.—Ed.)

Scientific Column

In this so-called Nineteenth Century Science is but too little considered in the nurseries of the rich and proud. But we are not like that.

It is not generally known that if you put bits of camphor in luke-warm water it will move about. If you drop sweet oil in, the camphor will dart away and then stop moving. But don’t drop any till you are tired of it, because the camphor won’t any more afterwards. Much amusement and instruction is lost by not knowing things like this.

If you put a sixpence under a shilling in a wine-glass, and blow hard down the side of the glass, the sixpence will jump up and sit on the top of the shilling. At least I can’t do it myself, but my cousin can. He is in the Navy.

Answers to Correspondents

Noël.—You are very poetical, but I am sorry to say it will not do.

Alice.—Nothing will ever make your hair curl, so it’s no use. Some people say it’s more important to tidy up as you go along. I don’t mean you in particular, but every one.

H. O.—We never said you were tubby, but the Editor does not know any cure.

Noël.—If there is any of the paper over when this newspaper is finished, I will exchange it for your shut-up inkstand, or the knife that has the useful thing in it for taking stones out of horses’ feet, but you can’t have it without.

H. O.—There are many ways how your steam engine might stop working. You might ask Dicky. He knows one of them. I think it is the way yours stopped.

Noël.—If you think that by filling the garden with sand you can make crabs build their nests there you are not at all sensible.

You have altered your poem about the battle of Waterloo so often, that we cannot read it except where the Duke waves his sword and says some thing we can’t read either. Why did you write it on blotting-paper with purple chalk?—Ed.

(Because You Know Who sneaked my pencil.—Noël.)

Poetry

The Assyrian came down like a wolf on the fold,
And the way he came down was awful, I’m told;
But it’s nothing to the way one of the Editors comes down on me,
If I crumble my bread-and-butter or spill my tea. Noël.

Curious Facts

If you hold a guinea-pig up by his tail his eyes drop out.

You can’t do half the things yourself that children in books do, making models or soon. I wonder why?—Alice.

If you take a date’s stone out and put in an almond and eat them together, it is prime. I found this out.—Sub-Editor.

If you put your wet hand into boiling lead it will not hurt you if you draw it out quickly enough. I have never tried this.—Dora.

The Purring Class

(Instructive Article)

If I ever keep a school everything shall be quite different. Nobody shall learn anything they don’t want to. And sometimes instead of having masters and mistresses we will have cats, and we will dress up in cat skins and learn purring. “Now, my dears,” the old cat will say, “one, two, three all purr together,” and we shall purr like anything.

She won’t teach us to mew, but we shall know how without teaching. Children do know some things without being taught.—Alice.

Poetry

(Translated into French by Dora)

Quand j’étais jeune et j’étais fou
J’achetai un violon pour dix-huit sous
Et tous les airs que je jouai
Était over the hills and far away.

Another piece of it

Mercie jolie vache qui fait
Bon lait pour mon déjeuner
Tous les matins tous les soirs
Mon pain je mange, ton lait je boire.

Recreations

It is a mistake to think that cats are playful. I often try to get a cat to play with me, and she never seems to care about the game, no matter how little it hurts.—H. O.

Making pots and pans with clay is fun, but do not tell the grown-ups. It is better to surprise them; and then you must say at once how easily it washes off—much easier than ink.—Dicky.

Sam Redfern, or the Bush Ranger’s Burial

By Dicky

“Well, Annie, I have bad news for you,” said Mr. Ridgway, as he entered the comfortable dining-room of his cabin in the Bush. “Sam Redfern the Bushranger is about this part of the Bush just now. I hope he will not attack us with his gang.”

“I hope not,” responded Annie, a gentle maiden of some sixteen summers.

Just then came a knock at the door of the hut, and a gruff voice asked them to open the door.

“It is Sam Redfern the Bushranger, father,” said the girl.

“The same,” responded the voice, and the next moment the hall door was smashed in, and Sam Redfern sprang in, followed by his gang.

Chapter II

Annie’s Father was at once overpowered, and Annie herself lay bound with cords on the drawing-room sofa. Sam Redfern set a guard round the lonely hut, and all human aid was despaired of. But you never know. Far away in the Bush a different scene was being enacted.

“Must be Injuns,” said a tall man to himself as he pushed his way through the brushwood. It was Jim Carlton, the celebrated detective. “I know them,” he added; “they are Apaches.” just then ten Indians in full war-paint appeared. Carlton raised his rifle and fired, and slinging their scalps on his arm he hastened towards the humble log hut where resided his affianced bride, Annie Ridgway, sometimes known as the Flower of the Bush.

Chapter III

The moon was low on the horizon, and Sam Redfern was seated at a drinking bout with some of his boon companions.

They had rifled the cellars of the hut, and the rich wines flowed like water in the golden goblets of Mr. Ridgway.

But Annie had made friends with one of the gang, a noble, good-hearted man who had joined Sam Redfern by mistake, and she had told him to go and get the police as quickly as possible.

“Ha! ha!” cried Redfern, “now I am enjoying myself!” He little knew that his doom was near upon him.

Just then Annie gave a piercing scream, and Sam Redfern got up, seizing his revolver. “Who are you?” he cried, as a man entered.

“I am Jim Carlton, the celebrated detective,” said the new arrival.

Sam Redfern’s revolver dropped from his nerveless fingers, but the next moment he had sprung upon the detective with the well-known activity of the mountain sheep, and Annie shrieked, for she had grown to love the rough Bushranger.

(To be continued at the end of the paper if there is room.)

Scholastic

A new slate is horrid till it is washed in milk. I like the green spots on them to draw patterns round. I know a good way to make a slate-pencil squeak, but I won’t put it in because I don’t want to make it common.—Sub-Editor.

Peppermint is a great help with arithmetic. The boy who was second in the Oxford Local always did it. He gave me two. The examiner said to him, “Are you eating peppermints?” And he said, “No, Sir.”

He told me afterwards it was quite true, because he was only sucking one. I’m glad I wasn’t asked. I should never have thought of that, and I could have had to say “Yes.”—Oswald.

The Wreck of the “Malabar”

By Noël

(Author of “A Dream of Ancient Ancestors.”) He isn’t really—but he put it in to make it seem more real.

Hark! what is that noise of rolling
Waves and thunder in the air?
’Tis the death-knell of the sailors
And officers and passengers of the good ship Malabar.

It was a fair and lovely noon
When the good ship put out of port
And people said “ah little we think
How soon she will be the elements’ sport.”

She was indeed a lovely sight
Upon the billows with sails spread.
But the captain folded his gloomy arms,
Ah—if she had been a life-boat instead!

See the captain stern yet gloomy
Flings his son upon a rock,
Hoping that there his darling boy
May escape the wreck.

Alas in vain the loud winds roared’
And nobody was saved.
That was the wreck of the Malabar,
Then let us toll for the brave.Noël.

Gardening Notes

It is useless to plant cherry-stones in the hope of eating the fruit, because they don’t!

Alice won’t lend her gardening tools again, because the last time Noël left them out in the rain, and I don’t like it. He said he didn’t.

Seeds and Bulbs

These are useful to play at shop with, until you are ready. Not at dinner-parties, for they will not grow unless uncooked. Potatoes are not grown with seed, but with chopped-up potatoes. Apple trees are grown from twigs, which is less wasteful.

Oak trees come from acorns. Every one knows this. When Noël says he could grow one from a peach stone wrapped up in oak leaves, he shows that he knows nothing about gardening but marigolds, and when I passed by his garden I thought they seemed just like weeds now the flowers have been picked.

A boy once dared me to eat a bulb.

Dogs are very industrious and fond of gardening. Pincher is always planting bones, but they never grow up. There couldn’t be a bone tree. I think this is what makes him bark so unhappily at night. He has never tried planting dog-biscuit, but he is fonder of bones, and perhaps he wants to be quite sure about them first.

Sam Redfern, or the Bushranger’s Burial

by Dicky

Chapter IV and Last

This would have been a jolly good story if they had let me finish it at the beginning of the paper as I wanted to. But now I have forgotten how I meant it to end, and I have lost my book about Red Indians, and all my Boys of England have been sneaked. The girls say “Good riddance!” so I expect they did it. They want me just to put in which Annie married, but I shan’t, so they will never know.

We have now put everything we can think of into the paper. It takes a lot of thinking about. I don’t know how grown-ups manage to write all they do. It must make their heads ache, especially lesson books.

Albert-next-door only wrote one chapter of the serial story, but he could have done some more if he had wanted to. He could not write out any of the things because he cannot spell. He says he can, but it takes him such a long time he might just as well not be able. There are one or two things more. I am sick of it, but Dora says she will write them in.

Legal Answer Wanted. A quantity of excellent string is offered if you know whether there really is a law passed about not buying gunpowder under thirteen.—Dicky.

The price of this paper is one shilling each, and sixpence extra for the picture of the Malabar going down with all hands. If we sell one hundred copies we will write another paper.

And so we would have done, but we never did. Albert-next-door’s uncle gave us two shillings, that was all. You can’t restore fallen fortunes with two shillings!